<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Refuge Counseling Co.</title>
    <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo" />
    <updated>2025-01-09T14:56:49-08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Experience</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/experience-v2.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/experience-v2.html</id>

        <updated>2024-12-13T16:20:25-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Experience &amp; Qualifications: I am a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist with the BBS, for the state of California. (LIC# LMFT106683) Education: Masters&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="align-center">Experience &amp; Qualifications:</div>
<div class="align-center">I am a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist with the BBS, for the state of California. (LIC# LMFT106683)</div>
<div class="align-center"> </div>
<div class="align-center">Education:</div>
<ul class="align-center">
<li>Masters of Science in Clinical Psychology from Vanguard University of Southern California</li>
<li>Bachelor of Arts in Psychology from Vanguard University of Southern California</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<div class="align-center">My experience in the field of mental health starts with working in level 12 and 14 group homes for adolescents 12-21 years old, supporting youth who are no longer able to live with their family or loved ones. I have provided therapeutic services in different environments to a variety of populations. This experience includes a community mental health clinic providing low-cost or no-cost individual and group therapy, Partial Hospitalization Programs (PHP) working with chronically mentally ill clients and those going through the most difficult times in their life, Intensive Outpatient Programs (IOP) for both adults and adolescents who need a higher level of care than traditional outpatient therapy, non-public school setting working with children and adolescents with IEPs who are unable to remain in a traditional classroom setting, public school setting as a school therapist to provide social emotional education and individual child therapy, and group practice working with individuals in-person and virtually.</div>
<div class="align-center"> </div>
<div class="align-center">I was also able to step into the role of a Program Director for a wraparound agency working with Department of Child and Family Services (DCFS) and Department of Mental Health (DMH), providing services to foster youth and families. In addition, I also gained experience as the Program Director for a PHP hospital-setting. It was in these leadership roles where I found another passion of mine - providing clinical supervision to the upcoming generation of therapists. </div>
<div class="align-center"> </div>
<div class="align-center">I truly believe my experiences in the mental health field have led me to this moment of having a private practice, and have given me the ability to help individuals in a unique way. </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Therapeutic Approach</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/modality.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/modality.html</id>

        <updated>2024-12-13T16:17:57-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The base of my therapy is most often utilizing the evidenced-based treatment of Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT). In your first session, we will&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="align-center">The base of my therapy is most often utilizing the evidenced-based treatment of Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT). In your first session, we will look at symptoms, behaviors, and goals to determine the best approach for your treatment. With DBT specifically, we look at: increasing effective coping skills, improving emotional regulation, building distress tolerance, and practicing effective communication, all while incorporating mindfulness. Other therapeutic modalities I often incorporate into my approach are as follows:</div>
<div> </div>
<div class="align-center">Cognitive Behavioral (CBT)<br>Culturally Sensitive<br>Family Systems<br>Person-Centered<br>Psychodynamic<br>Trauma Focused<br>Attachment </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/about-me-v2.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/about-me-v2.html</id>

        <updated>2024-12-07T10:53:17-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    My passion for helping others started at a very young age. I always knew I was going to be a helper of some&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/IMG_5018-2.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="1844" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-md.jpg 768w ,https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/media/posts/8/responsive/IMG_5018-2-2xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<p> </p>
<p>My passion for helping others started at a very young age. I always knew I was going to be a helper of some kind. After deciding on psychology, I went to Vanguard University of Southern California, where I received my Bachelor’s degree in psychology in 2010. I then went on to earn my Master’s of Science in Clinical Psychology in 2015 at Vanguard as well. Even while earning my degrees, I began to work in the mental health field. I also started my own journey in therapy, and felt and saw what a difference insight and healing makes. Then, as I started working towards my hours needed for my license of Marriage and Family Therapy, I dove into the field, and never looked back!</p>
<div> </div>
<div>In September of 2024, I decided to open my own practice. After 6 years of licensed experience, 10 years of working as a therapist, and over 12 years of working with those struggling with their mental health, I decided to use my experience in a way that is also sustainable for my health. Each and every role and position I have had the opportunity to be in has taught me so much. About mental health, this field, and myself.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I am incredibly grateful and excited to be able to get back to direct patient care and see clients one-on-one, in a space where I’ve seen so much healing take place. This work is so rewarding and I consider it a privilege to do this work.</div>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Specialties and Expertise</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/specialties-and-expertise.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/specialties-and-expertise.html</id>

        <updated>2024-11-27T15:30:07-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Services Individual therapy - with adults and youth 12 years and older. Family therapy sessions may be recommended or offered as-needed. Therapy for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="attributes-group align-left" data-v-1471e8aa="">
<h3 class="align-center">Services</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Individual therapy - with adults and youth 12 years and older. Family therapy sessions may be recommended or offered as-needed.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<ul>
<li class="attributes-group align-left">Therapy for grad psych students in need of personal therapy hours.<br><br></li>
<li class="attributes-group align-left">Clinical Supervision - Individual or Group Supervision can be provided on a contracted basis.<br><br></li>
<li class="attributes-group align-left">Educational Presentations or Workshops.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="align-left">Top Specialties</h2>
<p>Anxiety<br>Depression<br>Trauma<br>Life Transitions<br>Teen/adolescent issues<br>Parenting<br>Family Conflict<br>Relationship Issues<br>Parent Wounds</p>
<div data-v-1471e8aa=""> </div>
<div class="align-left" data-v-1471e8aa="">
<h2 class="align-left"> Proficient/experience in</h2>
<p>ADHD<br><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Anger Management<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Autism<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Behavioral Issues<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Childhood Trauma<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Codependency<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Coping Skills<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Grief<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">LGBTQ+<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Life Transitions<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Mood Disorders<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">School Issues<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Self Esteem<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Self-Harming<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Sexual Abuse<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Stress<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Suicidal Ideation<br></span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Thinking Disorders</span></p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Rates</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/rates.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/rates.html</id>

        <updated>2024-11-27T15:29:52-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    $250 is my top fee per session. I offer an income-based sliding scale for those who qualify. I also work with lien agreement&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> </p>
<ul>
<li>$250 is my top fee per session. I offer an income-based sliding scale for those who qualify. I also work with lien agreement clients.<br><br></li>
<li>$100 per session for clients in a Grad Psych program.<br><br></li>
<li>For clinical supervision, workshops, or educational presentations, my fees are negotiable.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact Us</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/contact-me.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/contact-me.html</id>

        <updated>2024-11-27T15:27:22-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Please email us at info@refugecounselingco.com A member of our team will contact you to schedule a free phone consultation and go over our&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>
<div class="section" data-v-581ad0bf="">
<p> </p>
<p class="msg msg--info align-center">Please email us at <a href="mailto:info@refugecounselingco.com">info@refugecounselingco.com</a></p>
<p class="align-center">A member of our team will contact you to schedule a free phone consultation and go over our services.  All sessions are currently online.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>FAQ</title>
        <author>
            <name>Refuge Counseling Co.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/faq.html"/>
        <id>https://tes54nsus0lfc.github.io/RefugeCounselingCo/faq.html</id>

        <updated>2024-11-27T15:27:18-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This depends on your presenting problems, but, usually, no less than 8 sessions. Some clients may require or choose long-term therapy for ongoing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> </p>
<h3><strong><em>How long is therapy?</em></strong></h3>
<blockquote>
<p>This depends on your presenting problems, but, usually, no less than 8 sessions. Some clients may require or choose long-term therapy for ongoing problems, and other clients are able to address targeted issues within 8-10 sessions. It all depends on your needs, and this will be discussed and revisited throughout treatment.</p>
</blockquote>
<div> </div>
<h3><strong><em>What can I expect? </em></strong></h3>
<blockquote><address>A safe, non-judgmental environment to discuss what your problems are, how they are affecting you, and what changes you would like to make. Therapy is NOT advice. It is a space where we will identify patterns, help connect dots, process difficult emotions and experiences, and identify tools that may be more helpful than current ways of coping. </address></blockquote>
<div> </div>
<div>
<h3><em><strong>Are you faith-based?</strong></em></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>I am a Christian, and incorporate faith and spirituality into therapy when my clients request to approach therapy from that worldview. The modalities I use for therapy do not require a Christian or faith-based approach, and I always consider and respect the spiritual beliefs of my clients. I have worked with clients from many backgrounds, and only bring faith/spiritual beliefs into the therapeutic space when the client invites it.</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div> </div>
<h3><strong>How do I get started?</strong></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>I offer a free 15-minute consultation, so you can simply call, text, or email to schedule a no-obligation phone call to see if I'm the right fit for you.</div>
</blockquote>
<div> </div>
<h3><em><strong>How do I know who the right therapist is for me?</strong></em></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>Ask yourself the following: Does the therapist list the issues you are struggling with? Does the therapist feel like someone you could be open with in time? Are you okay with their gender, approach to therapy, and mode of therapy (in-person or virtual)?</div>
</blockquote>
<div> </div>
<h3><strong><em>Do you take insurance?</em></strong></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>No, I do not. I do work with lien agreements and offer an income-based sliding scale. </div>
</blockquote>
<div> </div>
<h3><em><strong>How much does this cost?</strong></em></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>My fee per session is $250, unless a lower fee is agreed upon, based on your income. If you are a grad psych student, I charge $100 per session. </div>
</blockquote>
<div> </div>
<h3><em><strong>Do you have</strong></em><em><strong> availability?</strong></em></h3>
<blockquote>
<div>Yes! I currently have availability during the week-days. </div>
</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
